DAVID

Address 291 / 164 Blocs 77

Sukhumvit Road, Soi 77 Phra Khanong, Wattana

10110 Bangkok

Mobile (+66) 089 152 7147

E-mail d.badstuebner@outlook.com

Nationality German



# SUMMARY STATEMENT

BADSTÜBNER

IT professional with more than 15 years of experience with a focus on IT development and project management in an international environment. Highly organized, detail-orientated and independent in fast-paced multitasking environments; able to strategize and prioritize efficiently to accomplish objectives with timeliness, creativity, enthusiasm and cultural sensitivity.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

09.2015 - 01.2016

## IT Consultant (Chief Technology Officer)

Swiss Magic Limited., Bangkok, Thailand

## Responsibilities:

- Quality Assurance
- Development for customized projects
- Plan and structure of work assignments and team structures
- Monitor, evaluate, formulate, implement and enforce processes affecting project execution, delivery and skills training and development

# Achievement:

- Development of a Quality Assurance Guideline for Swiss Magic
- Setup and implementation of the Develop Environment for Swiss Magic
- Project management for Trucksearch24.ch, a portal for buying and renting trucks and cars in Switzerland.

01.2006 - presently

## **IT Consultant and Web Developer**

Germany / Thailand

## Responsibilities:

- Business development
- Project planning and coordination of internal workforce and external freelancer
- Develop of Enterprise Software as web applications, including usability and process optimization
- Software enhancements for mobile use (API-Interface)
- Provide support and user training
- Selection and design of server environment
- Structure of the database layout
- Software selection, evaluation and extension

# Achievements:

- Development, launch and support "TeamTimer", a schedule system for teams and companies; including import and export functions for Outlook and iCal dates as well as DATEV tax statements, implementation of statistic functions time registrations
- Software selection process and launch of an internal knowledge management system for Treif Maschinenbau GmbH for collection, storage and management of company know-how, Including a reward system

- Launch of a stock market information portal for Investment24 and Capital Innovation
- Various extensions for MERViSOFT's enterprise software "Support-Tool" and "Lead-Tool" to support and improve the customer support and merge the lead handling in one tool for all connected subcontractors and partners
- Project management and set-up of an Online-Shop based on the OXID shop system with connections to the payment providers

### Customers:

- TeamTimer
- Treif Maschinenbau GmbH
- MERViSOFT-GmbH
- Investment24 AG
- Capital Innovation AG

## 04.1999 - 12.2005

## **Developer and Project Manager**

MERViSOFT-GmbH, Wiesbaden, Germany

#### Responsibilities:

- Enterprise Software Development
- Quality Management
- Process Management
- Software Support

#### Achievements:

- Development and launch of File Management System for the construction phase of the "Allianz-Arena" in Munich
- Support-Tool to support the software development department and handle customer inquiries
- Lead-Tool to support the distribution department

# **EDUCATION / APPRENTICESHIP / Trainee**

06.2011 - 07.2012	Master of Business Administration (MBA) in General Management International Institute of Ramkhamhaeng University, Bangkok Faculty: Business Administration
08.2006 - 07.2010	Bachelor of Arts (BA) in Media Management Rhein Main University of Applied Sciences, Wiesbaden, Germany
08.2000 - 06.2002	IT-Specialist for Application Development Friedrich-Ebert Berufsschule and MERViSOFT-GmbH, Wiesbaden, Germany Apprenticeship as IT-Specialist of Application Development

# Skills

Languages German Native Speaker

English Fluent

Thai Basic proficiency in spoken and written Thai

Moderation Group and conflict management techniques, teambuilding and creativities skills

Idea-Management Techniques to develop solutions and ideas, like Brainstorming, Mind-Mapping, Osborn

Checklist or Poison-antidote-technology

Presentation Training for presentation techniques and skills, Rhetoric and Body Language

Coding PHP, HTML5, JavaScript , CSS, Codelgniter, Laravel, JQuery, Bootstrap, OXID,

Wordpress, MySQL, Oracle